Hello friends, my name is Jai Sharma and
welcome to our
YouTube1 about the company Chola MS
General Insurance. Friends, if
you use a car, you
use a two-wheeler, then you must have
heard the name of this company at some point or the other. So
friends, today we will talk
about this company, what is this company like,
what is its claim ratio, how does it give claims,
what problems do you face,
what things does it offer you. So we
will talk about this company. So
friends, before moving ahead, subscribe to our channel
because you will keep getting notifications of such
videos that we bring for you. So
let's start
[music].
Now friends, let's talk about this group. First of all,
friends, the name of the company
is Chola MS General Insurance.
Its other name is Chola Mandalam and
this entire group comes
under the Murugappa Group. Now, here,
Chola Mandalam is Chola MS.
I am talking about Murugappa Group and Sottom
Insurance Company. These two companies together are
Murugappa Insurance Company of India.  Group and
Sumom Insurance is a Japanese insurance
company. So, these two companies
together run a general insurance company in India under the name Chola MS.
Now friends, if we
talk about Chola MS, then Chola MS
is a part of the Murugappa Group. Both of them
run only Chola MS. Apart from this, if we
talk about Murugappa Group, then they have many
companies. Apart from this, in India,
Kavar Andam Universal, CD Power EID,
Parry Shanti Gears, Chola Mandalam Finance,
Coro Mandal International Tube Investment,
BSA Hercules, everyone must have heard about it.
Montra Electric is a bicycle manufacturing company.
If we talk about Murugappa Group, then
all these companies
come under the Murugappa Group. If we talk about insurance, then
Chola
MS General Insurance is
run by these two companies together and does
general insurance work in India.
Talking about the products, if we talk about insurance, then the people who
sell these companies include motor insurance, which will cover all your two-
wheelers, four-wheelers and commercial vehicles.
Health insurance,
travel insurance, home insurance, personal
accident, marine insurance and crop
insurance. So, all these insurance companies are run by this
company.  It provides you any
service. If you want all these things in insurance,
then you
can get it from Chola Middlem or Chola MS.
Talking about branches, there are about 198
branches in India. You will find branches all over India.
More than a thousand employees work for them
in all the branches. And if we talk about intermediate
agents, then
more than 30000 of them work for them in India. It is a
very big group, it is not a small company.
And if we talk about the website, if you
want more information about this company, then
they have a website.
[Music]
So the claim settlement ratio of this company is
96% for motor insurance.
Talking about cashless garage, it is more than 6900%.
This means that you will get cash in almost all the
cities and all parts of India.
Talking about the settlement charges, then the
company charges you 5% as
settlement charges. Talking about no claim
bonus, then you get no claim bonus
up to 50%.  That you
get in all the companies, here also you are going to get the same, there is
instant policy issue,
so friends, whenever you issue a policy,
you get it issued through someone, you issue it online,
your policy gets
issued there instantly, if your policy
is in continuity, if your policy has already
expired, then there will be an inspection of the vehicle,
after that the policy will be
issued there, all India presence, so
friends, the presence of this company is all India,
anywhere you live in any city,
if you want to get Chola MAC insurance, then
you can get it and
you will get its cashless all over India there,
now friends, let's move ahead and talk
that if you take insurance for your vehicle
from Chola MAC, then which
insurances can you take and what
add-ons can you do in it, so first of all let's
talk about third party, friends,
you can take third party from here and whenever
you take a third party policy,
you can add two-three add-ons in it, like the
first one that comes is PA cover of 15 lakhs, in whose name  If you have a
car with someone, you can take PA cover in their name. It is a
cover of Rs 15 lakh and is a
mandatory cover. If you do not take it, then the
company can reject your claim there as well.
Talking about number two,
driver cover, you
can take driver cover along with third party. Let's talk about
passenger cover and all the passengers who
sit in your car, suppose you have a five
seater car or a seven seater car,
accordingly you can take passenger cover for your five unknown passengers
or for seven unknown passengers.
Now let's
talk about on-damage, friends,
you can purchase on-damage policy from here.
Suppose your third party
is running from somewhere, if you have purchased a new car in
which you have got a nine year third party,
you have got a one year first party, if you want to get first party
on-damage for two years, then
you can take that separately as well.
Your third party is running with some other company. If
you have taken on-damage from here, then along with
on-damage you can take zero down payment and
get your consumer cover.  You
can take engine and gear box cover, return to
invoice, key replacement,
roadside assistance,
personal belongings, tyre cover, rim protection,
conveyance allowance, pay as you drive and EMI
cover. So,
all these covers, if you are taking an on-damage policy from this company, then
you
can make separate purchases here. If you take on-damage, then you will be able to add all these covers.
You will
not be able to add any of these covers with third party. If you
take third party, then you will be able to add these covers,
but you will not be
able to take all these covers with on-damage. So, what I mean to say is that
all these three covers will be available only with third party
and you will get these along with on-damage
here. Now let's talk about comprehensive cover. It is a
combination of both. In this comprehensive cover,
you get both third party and on-damage
coverage. Within a single policy,
you have two separate sections,
A section, B section, C section. So, by
creating all the sections in it, this third party on-damage and everything else.  It is
added to it, it is
called comprehensive policy, so
comprehensive means you are getting third party,
on damage, so the ones
that are to be added with the third party,
you will get these here as well and the ones that are to be
added with on damage,
you will get these here as well, so
whenever you take a compass policy, you can get all the things,
but whenever you take separate
policies, whether you take third party separately
or take on damage separately, then you will be able to add these things here
and you will be able to add these things here,
now friends let's talk about whatever
insurance you have taken, whether you have
taken third party, you have taken first party,
comprehensive or you have taken on damage, then what things does the
company cover after taking these insurances, so
friends first of all let's talk about
third party liability with third party, in which
someone's injury, someone's death or
someone's property damage, all this is
for the other person, you hit someone, he
died, he got injured, his hand got broken or his
property, the other person's
property got damaged  If any property gets
damaged, be it a car, a bike or someone's house, then the
company is liable there and pays for it on your behalf. So,
loss due to
fire, accident, theft and explosion will be available
in your on-damage or
comprehensive where your vehicle
ID will also be there, the company will pay you accordingly. So,
if the vehicle catches fire, the vehicle meets with an
accident, the vehicle is stolen or there is an
explosion in the vehicle, the vehicle bursts, then
in that condition the company will pay you
whatever your vehicle ID is. The
company will pay you there. If you have
taken RTI, then the company will pay you as per
RTI. If
your vehicle gets any damage due to natural disaster,
then the company will pay you there too. If
red-bite rats cut the wires
or cause any damage to your vehicle, then the
company will cover that too here. Personal
accidental cover for owner up to Rs 15 lakh, driver up to Rs
2 lakh and passenger up to Rs 2 lakh. So
here the company covers the passenger and driver.  It will do it
for Rs 2 lakh, here also your
injury death will be like this and if we talk about the owner, then there
is a cover of Rs 1 lakh for the owner, if
something happens to the owner while driving the car,
then in the case of the owner, the company will pay Rs 1
lakh to the owner or his nominee, let's
talk about coverage for CNG
LPG bi-fuel kit, so friends, if
you have bought your car with
CNG fitted, which has come from the company with CNG fitted, then
all the things will be covered in it,
but if you get CNG fitted from outside
or LPG fitted from outside,
then in that condition you have to update the CNG
on your insurance, only then the
company will pay you, so keep this in mind that
whenever you get CNG installed on your car or get an
LPG kit installed, then get it
updated on your insurance, only then it will be
covered, otherwise that cover is not going to be there,
so friends,
whenever you take insurance for all these things, you should take third party
insurance, you should take a comprehensive policy
or on  Take damage, if you
take a comprehensive policy then all these things will be covered in it,
if you take only own damage then this, this
and this will be covered for you, if you
take only third party then in third party
your third party liability, personal
accident and here coverage for CNG will also be
there, so the company covers this for you,
now let's talk about
which things the company does not cover, friends,
if you take insurance from the company then
in some conditions the companies, this company or
other companies do
not cover the damages that you suffer, what
is that condition, driving without a valid license, if you are
driving your vehicle, you do
not have a license, your license has expired
or your license is
not applicable to drive the vehicle, then in such a condition the
company will reject your claim there
and you will not get anything there,
if you take drugs,
you are driving the vehicle after taking drugs, you are drink
and drive, then even in that condition the
company will not pay you anything, damage
due to war for an enemy, if any fight  If there is a
war going on or there is a
war going on with some other country or there is a civil
war going on, then in that condition also the
company will not pay you anything, it completely
depends on the company, if the company
wants then the company can pay you,
otherwise the company does not pay here,
apart from that if we talk about sports activities then if
you do sports activities with your car or do
some racing
then the company does not pay you anything there also,
whatever your expenses will be,
you will have to pay the total expense from your pocket,
so the company does not cover all these conditions,
this company also does not cover it,
along with that the insurance
companies also do not cover it, now
friends let's talk about discount that
whenever you take a policy from this company,
what discounts does the company give you here,
friends first of all let's talk about
on-discount, so friends you should take the policy
online, you should take it from the policy agent, from whomever
you take the policy, you get on-damage
discount in the policy and as soon as
you go to the company's portal or on the
portal of any online broker like policy bazaar, you can book
your car there  If you enter the details of the vehicle then it
automatically avails the on-demand
discount there, you will
not have to do anything for this, you just have to
enter the vehicle number or the details of the vehicle,
whatever details of your vehicle are there,
enter the details of the vehicle there and it will avail it automatically
there, let's talk about no claim
discount, so friends,
this discount is given as per your
old no claim bonus, if you have taken a
claim in the last year then you will get
zero, whether your no claim
bonus is 50, 45, 35, 25 or whatever it is,
as soon as you take a claim, you will come to zero, you will
start from zero again, 20,
next year 25, then 35, 45 and
50, let's talk about voluntary deductible, so
friends, this voluntary deductible is that
whenever you take a claim for the vehicle, you have to pay a
fee charge of Rs. 000 or 000, it depends on the
case, so this
deductible of yours is Rs. 000 but you
can increase it  Yes, you can make it 3000 or
5000, there your
premium will be reduced instantly at that time
but whenever you go to take a claim, then
in that claim, instead of 1000, the
amount you have chosen, 3000 or 5000, then
you will have to choose that amount there,
you can take instant discount but
it will cause you loss, you should not take it, let's
talk about anti-thif device, if you have
installed any anti-thif device in your vehicle,
any GPS, then there
also the company gives you discount and
you can save some money there, AI
members, if you
are a member of Automotive Association of India, then you can
get some discount there, so some
money of yours will be reduced there also, let's talk about
TPPD discount, it is
called third party property damage, so
you get this discount also but there
is your limit.  That limit of lakh reduces to
just 000, so there is no benefit in
taking this TPPD discount there too.
Now friends, let's talk about the
premium. Whenever you
get third party insurance,
you are going to get a fixed premium for it. No matter in
which city you live in India, you are going to get a
fixed premium for your vehicle everywhere.
You get insurance from anywhere, no matter
in which city you live, you will get the
same insurance. The only difference will be in the
CC, how many CC is your vehicle. So
friends, if your vehicle is less than 1000 CC,
then any vehicle, be it
[music]
wagon-r, for all, the third party will come to you
9318. Apart from this, some money will increase in it.
Like if you add your CNG, then your 9318 will
increase plus GST. Apart from that, if you
add your PA cover, add passenger cover,
add driver cover, then that will
increase a little bit with your third party. Let's talk about on-damage and
comprehensive. Friends, the
premium for comprehensive and on-damage is not fixed,
it completely depends.
Now what are the conditions on different conditions
What is the IDV of your vehicle If the IDV is less then the
premium will be less If the IDV is more then the
premium will be more The
difference that comes according to cubic capacity will be there here
also Your third party is included in compressed
Which zone is your zone Zone A
B C A Like Delhi Mumbai Chennai
What is it that you have more chances of
your vehicle getting into an accident There are
more chances of getting claims due to vehicles getting damaged
So your premium will always be higher in zone A It will be a
little less in zone B It will be even less
in zone C If the fuel type of your
vehicle is diesel then the premium will be higher If it is
petrol then the premium will be lower If it is CNG then the premium will be lower If it is
electric then it is based on the model It is based on the
variant Which add-ons are you
adding Zero Dump Consumption Ball Engine
Tyre RTI So the premium will be based on all the add-ons
So your premium is going to be fixed in third party
but there is no fix in On Damage and Compressed
So in this way your
premium is going to be decided here
Now friends  Let's talk about detection
that whenever you take a policy, after taking the policy,
when a claim comes, then
what are the detections that can happen to you in it, so friends, the
first direction is of file charge,
whenever you take a claim, if your vehicle is
less than 1500 cc, then it will cost you Rs. 000, if it is
above 1500 cc, then it will cost you Rs.
000. Let's talk about salvage charge,
whatever part is changed in your vehicle,
it will cost you Rs. 5, whatever its cost will be,
here as a salvage company is going to charge you Rs. 5. If we
talk about depreciation, then you have depreciation on 30 to 50 percent
if your policy is not zero dope,
but if it is zero dope, then
depreciation is not going to happen there.
Talking about consumer bills, it is
also necessary to take cover for consumer bills, if you do
not take cover for consumer, then the cost of consumer
items will be up to Rs. 10 percent.  The
company can charge you around 8 to 10 rupees
there too. Now
friends, let's talk about the documents
that whenever you take a policy or
you make a claim, then which
documents are going to be required by you, so
friends, let's talk first, for policy purchase, first of all
you need a PAN card.
Policy is not issued without a PAN card.
From January 1, 2023,
policy is not issued without a PAN card without KYC. If you do
not have a PAN card, then your Form 16 will be put there,
your Form 60 will be put there,
your KYC will be done in the same way and along with it, your Aadhar
card will be put, so PAN card
is mandatory, you need RC. You should have a previous
policy. If you are doing a continuation
policy, then if you are doing a third party policy, then it will
work even without a previous policy
and if the insurance of your vehicle has
expired for more than 90 days, then there is
no need for premium. Your previous policy
can be insured there after inspection. Along with this,
your GST certificate is required. If
your vehicle company  If the vehicle is in the name of then the
company's PAN card and the GST
certificate of A, all these documents will be required.
Talking about the claim,
your PAN card will be required, that of the individual, or
if the vehicle is in the name of the company, then the company's
PAN card will be required, Aadhar card will be required,
in the case of an individual, in the case of a company,
your GST certificate will be required, along with that, the
RC insurance policy of the vehicle, your
driving license, whether yours or the
driver's, along with a claim form, so
all these documents are required whenever you buy a policy,
and whenever you go to make a claim, you should have all these
documents with you. Now
friends, finally let's talk about support,
whenever you buy a policy or
you want to buy a policy, you need to get an endorsement in the policy, you want to make a
claim,
then whom should you talk to? Friends,
talking about support, their customer care number
is 18208 5544,
you can call this number for all the things you need to do to purchase a policy, to make a claim, to make an endorsement,
you will
get all the help here on this number.  If we talk about the email ID, it is
customer@chms.com.
This is the company's email ID. If you need to
send documents to the company or
you don't want to call, you want to email directly
with the documents. Then you
can send your concern through email and
you will also receive a reward by email. If you want, you can
send 'Hi' to WhatsApp number 23443.
From there, you will get menu options
and you can choose the service you want.
Talking about the website, the
company's website is
www.cholainsurance.com. If
you want more information about the company,
you can visit this website and
get more information about the company. Now friends, let's talk
about this company and our personal
experience. Friends, the company
is good. The company has been operating in India since 2001. It has been
almost 24 years since the company started working. The
company is a Japanese company.
Sum Tomo Insurance works in collaboration with it.  I've been
working in India for almost 24 years, so
friends, look, no company is
bad, all companies are good. It
depends on the company's service, how the
company is conducting the survey,
how quickly the company is clearing the claims. In this case,
Chola Insurance is fine. We have taken many claims.
We have taken two-wheeler claims,
we have taken four-wheeler claims.
In both the cases, the company has easily
passed the claim. There may be a delay of a day or two in the survey,
but you get the claim. The
company does not refuse, the company does not indulge in
drama. The company has deliberately
not rejected your claim. If your claim is
genuine, then you will get the claim there. It does not matter
which company it is. If your claim is genuine, the
company will pay the claim. But if
your claim is not genuine, then the company
can hold the claim there. These things are
applicable with all the companies, no matter
how good or bad the company is. The
same condition is with C MLM and C AS. The
company is good.
Till now, none of our claims have been stuck in all the claims we have taken.
We got all the claims there easily, whether it was for a
two-wheeler or a four-wheeler,
we did not face any problem in the claim till now,
neither did we face any problem in the survey, nor did
we face any problem in reimbursement. We have
also taken a claim wherever there
is cashless, and there was no problem there either.
Even in reimbursement, our money
came to our account within 15 to 20 days. And
friends, the most important thing is that whenever you
take any policy, whether you take it from Chola MS or from any other
company, do check in your nearby service center
that which company
is cashless in your nearby service center, get
insurance from the company which is cashless.
Otherwise, you will have to pay the money first
and later the money will
come to your account, then you will have to get it reimbursed,
it may take 15 to 20 days.
If you need money immediately, then
go for cash and definitely call the nearby company to know
which company is cashless,
get the insurance done accordingly and
you will not face any problem in whatever claim you get.
So friends, this was my video today
about MS company, so friends,
do tell us how you liked this
video, if you liked the video then
like the video and subscribe to the channel
and if you feel that this
video of ours is helpful then
you can also share this video with your friends and
in your friends' groups,
thank you.